<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PersonalProjects on </title>
    <link>/tags/personalprojects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PersonalProjects on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/personalprojects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2021, Publication &amp; Life</title>
      <link>/blog/2021-publication-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021-publication-life/</guid>
      <description>I Am A Published Author?It has happened! My thesis has been published in Behavior Research Methods!
https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-021-01582-w
I began writing my thesis for the Concurrent Degree Program back in 2019. It was pretty surreal when I think back to 2019, the thesis started out as a blank word document with barely any words. Back then, I was struggling to piece together coherent sentences to form the introduction as I had to parse through the highly technical literature with little knowledge of the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Most Popular Modules in NUS Psychology</title>
      <link>/blog/most-popular-modules-in-nus-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/most-popular-modules-in-nus-psychology/</guid>
      <description>I embarked on an interesting project during the circuit-breaker period in Singapore where I used past bidding statistics from NUSMods to find the most popular Honors, Lab and Elective modules in NUS Psychology. For those who are currently in NUS or kept up with the news, you may have heard that the bidding system (CORS) was recently scrapped and replaced by a balloting system. Even though bidding is no longer used, I believe that the information of the popularity of modules is still relevant for balloting, which require students to rank their preferences.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>