<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on </title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2021, Publication &amp; Life</title>
      <link>/blog/2021-publication-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021-publication-life/</guid>
      <description>I Am A Published Author?It has happened! My thesis has been published in Behavior Research Methods!
https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-021-01582-w
I began writing my thesis for the Concurrent Degree Program back in 2019. It was pretty surreal when I think back to 2019, the thesis started out as a blank word document with barely any words. Back then, I was struggling to piece together coherent sentences to form the introduction as I had to parse through the highly technical literature with little knowledge of the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filtering Methods In R</title>
      <link>/blog/filtering-methods-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/filtering-methods-in-r/</guid>
      <description>One of the greatest and worst things about using R is that there are so many different methods to tackle the same problem. Every time I become aware of an alternative method, I start to think thoughts such as “Is this better than my method?”, “Does this always give the same results as my current method?”.
Filtering is one scenario when these thoughts surface, there are multiple ways to filter data but what are the actual differences between them?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NUS Psychology Concurrent Degree Program Review: Part 3</title>
      <link>/blog/nus-psychology-concurrent-degree-program-review-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/nus-psychology-concurrent-degree-program-review-part-3/</guid>
      <description>Read part 2 here!
Year 5: Thesis Submission Time!Year 5 was the so-called final lap as a CDP student. Don’t be fooled into thinking that you have 2 years to complete your thesis, the thesis is due on the fourth week of your final semester so it was more like 1.5 years. At this point I was already reviewing my results and writing the manuscript. There were a few hiccups here and there, one particular panic point was when I found mistakes in some of my code, which resulted in me running some rather last-minute simulations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NUS Psychology Concurrent Degree Program Review: Part 2</title>
      <link>/blog/nus-psychology-concurrent-degree-program-review-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/nus-psychology-concurrent-degree-program-review-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Read part 1 here!
Year 4 Semester 2The second semester of the CDP was a research and statistics fiesta for me as I took two graduate level research modules and worked on my thesis.
PL5222 Multivariate Statistics In PsychologyPL5225 Structural Equation ModelingOverall, I greatly enjoyed this semester as the modules were all highly practical. The focus of these modules was to build sufficient understanding and confidence such that we could apply advanced statistical and research techniques to answer research questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Most Popular Modules in NUS Psychology</title>
      <link>/blog/most-popular-modules-in-nus-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/most-popular-modules-in-nus-psychology/</guid>
      <description>I embarked on an interesting project during the circuit-breaker period in Singapore where I used past bidding statistics from NUSMods to find the most popular Honors, Lab and Elective modules in NUS Psychology. For those who are currently in NUS or kept up with the news, you may have heard that the bidding system (CORS) was recently scrapped and replaced by a balloting system. Even though bidding is no longer used, I believe that the information of the popularity of modules is still relevant for balloting, which require students to rank their preferences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NUS Psychology Concurrent Degree Program Review</title>
      <link>/blog/nus-psychology-concurrent-degree-program-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/nus-psychology-concurrent-degree-program-review/</guid>
      <description>I just recently graduated after ending my last finals in May and will be starting work soon. I decided to take some time to reflect on my experience with the CDP program and share what it was like in CDP Psychology. The program had its ups and downs but overall I would say that it had slightly more ups.
Year 3 Semester 1/2: ApplicationI first heard about the program in my Y2S2 and found that I met most of the requirements for the program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NUS Psychology Concurrent Degree Program. Should I Apply?</title>
      <link>/blog/should-i-apply-for-the-nus-psychology-concurrent-degree-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/should-i-apply-for-the-nus-psychology-concurrent-degree-program/</guid>
      <description>Every year, the department of Psychology in NUS sends out little postcards to the second-year undergraduates inviting them to apply for the Concurrent Degree Program (CDP). More often than not, these postcards are met with confusion over what this program actually is. The department website gives a good introduction to what the program offers and this post aims to complement the website. Providing a more student-centric explanation/reflection about the program and the frequently asked questions (from juniors) that are not found on the website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The First Post</title>
      <link>/blog/firstpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/firstpost/</guid>
      <description>The first post of the blog. I created this website with the intention of using it as a portfolio to link to various projects. But I got sucked into the deep rabbit hole of web designing and blogging that I decided to sacrifice one day to plow through numerous guides and documentation to create this spiffy site which can also blog.
Below are the key resources that I have consulted.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>